Freedom. Country. Honor. Passion. To save his best
friend, one man must risk everything he loves.
The Four Feathers is a action, adventure, drama film directed by Shekhar Kapur.
A young British officer resigns his post when he learns of his regiment's
plan to ship out to the Sudan for the conflict with the Mahdi.
His friends and fiancée send him four white feathers as
symbols of what they view as his cowardice.
To redeem his honor, he disguises himself as an
Arab and secretly saves their lives.
Harry Faversham, played by Heath Ledger.
Jack Durrance, played by Wes Bentley.
Ethne Eustace, played by Kate Hudson.
Abou Fatma, played by Djimon Hounsou.
Colonel Hamilton, played by Alex Jennings.
William Trench, played by Michael Sheen.
The Four Feathers is a 2002 war drama film directed by Shekhar Kapur and
starring Heath Ledger, Wes Bentley, Djimon Hounsou and Kate Hudson.
Set during the British Army's Gordon Relief Expedition (late 1884 to early 1885) in Sudan, well after
the formation of Mahdiyya, it tells the story of a young man accused of cowardice.
This film, with altered plot events, is the latest in a long line of
cinematic adaptations of the 1902 novel The Four Feathers by A.E.W.
Other versions of the story have been set in the
1890s, with different battle events.
It was roughly based on the White Feather Campaign during World War I.
The Four Feathers was released on 20 September 2002 by Paramount Pictures in the
United States and by Miramax International in international markets.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed
$29 million against a $35 million budget.
The film explores themes of army, escape, bravery, loyalty, british empire.
The tone is emotional.